So, we have the general layout of our MLP,
我们了解了此 MLP 的设计
and we're training this model to classify
现在要训练此模型
10 types of clothing in the fashion M-ness data set.
对 Fashion-MNIST 数据集中的 10 种服饰进行分类
We really just want to look at
我们的目的是看看
how a model trains when it's given different initial weights.
在给定不同初始权重时 模型的训练效果如何
So, I want to start off with a simple example for initializing weights.
先从一个简单的权重初始化示例开始
Kind of the simplest idea for setting
设置模型权重的最简单策略
your model weights is to just set them as a small constant value.
或许是将它们设为很小的常量
Say, setting them all to be zero or all to one.
例如全设为 0 或 1
Consistency seems like it could be a good solution because you might think
保持一致似乎是个不错的策略
that you don't want to start out by giving more weight to one node than any other.
因为我们想在开始时某个节点的权重就比其他节点都要大
There are a few ways to initialize the weights of the network,
初始化网络权重有几种方式
and in this case I'm going to actually pass in a constant weight variable.
我将传入一个 constant_weight 变量
This will give me the ability to pass in a constant weight when I instantiate a model.
以便在实例化模型时能够传入常量权重
The next thing I want to do is actually use this constant weight.
下一步是使用此常量权重
Inside the init function of our model,
在模型的 init 函数中
I'm going to check if a constant weight has been passed in.
检查是否传入了常量权重
Let's say I've passed in a constant way of zero,
假设传入了常量值 0
then we enter this IF statement.
然后进入这个 if 语句
This looks at every module or layer in our model.
它会查看模型中的每个模块/层级
Then it says, let's check the layer type.
然后它会检查层级类型
For every linear layer,
对于每个线性层级
I'm going to set the parameter weights to a constant value using nn.init.constant.
我将使用 nn.init.constant 将参数权重设为常量值
This takes in the weights we want to set from
输入参数是我们要设置的模块权重
our module and a constant weight value, which we passed in.
以及传入的常量权重值
I'm doing the exact same thing for our module bias,
模块偏差所做的初始化操作完全一样
only I'm setting the bias to zero.
但是我将偏差的常数值设为 0
So, all I had to do to set the weights is to specify how I want to initialize
要设置权重 我只需指定如何初始化每个线性层级
each linear layer and then use the nn.init library to help set those values.
然后使用 nn.init 库帮助设置这些值
This library includes a lot of common initialization schemes that we'll go over.
此库包含很多常见的初始化方案 稍后我会讲解的
Okay. Next, I actually need to instantiate
接下来我需要使用两组不同的常量权重
two different kinds of models with two different constant weights.
实例化两种不同的模型
Here, I'm going to create one model_0 with a constant weight of zero,
在这里使用常量权重 0 创建一个模型 model_0
and I'll create another model_1 with a constant weight of all ones.
然后使用常量权重全为 1 创建另一个模型 model_1
I'm going to create these models,
我将创建这些模型
then using my helpers functions,
然后使用辅助函数
I'm actually going to compare these two models and how they perform over two epics.
比较这两个模型在两个周期后的效果
So, I'll turn these into a list,
将这些变成列表
all zeros and ones,
全为 0 和全为 1
giving a title to each model,
每个模型设置一个名称
and then I'm going to compare the initial weights using the helpers function.
然后使用辅助函数比较初始权重
This cell may take a few moments to run as these models go through two epics of training.
这个单元格可能需要一些运行时间来让这两个模型都经过两轮训练
Here's the resulting plot.
这是生成的结果图表
You can see that a model that starts out with all ones as
可以看到权重全初始化为 1 的模型
weights starts out with an extremely high initial loss.
初始损失非常高
Usually for something with cross entropy loss,
通常对于交叉熵损失来说
I'm expecting a value in the single digits.
损失值通常仅为个位数
You can also see that when a model is initialized with all zeros,
还可以看出 当模型权重全初始化为 0 时
this line just sort of remains flat over time and doesn't change.
这条线似乎一直都保持平坦不变
The loss never really decreases.
损失没有降低
So, what exactly is happening here?
到底发生了什么？
Let's talk a bit about our model that starts out with a constant weight of zero.
我们再看看权重初始化为常量 0 的模型
In this case, every single hidden node is going to
在这种情形下 每个隐藏节点
respond to the inputs it sees in the exact same way.
将完全按照相同的方式对输入做出响应
It'll multiply all of these inputs by
它将所有输入乘以常量权重 0
a constant weight of zero and then add all of them up.
然后将它们加起来
This behavior repeats in the second layer where all the weights are
第二层的权重都是 0 因此这种行为还会重复
zero and again in the third producing a series of class scores.
在第三层生成一系列类别分数
Now, in any training process,
在任何训练流程中
these class scores will not be very accurate at first,
这些类别分数一开始不会太准确
but that's okay as long as you can learn from any mistakes.
但是只要能从错误里汲取经验再调整就行了
But in the case of all zero initial weights,
但是对于初始权重全为 0 的情形
when you go to calculate the cross entropy loss and use
当你计算交叉熵损失
backpropagation to identify sources of error,
并使用反向传播确定错误来源时
it all of the sudden becomes very hard to see which weights,
忽然间很难判断
which nodes are responsible for making any errors.
哪个权重/节导致了错误的发生
Because the weights were all zero in the hidden layers,
因为隐藏层中的所有权重都为 0
all the gradients that tell us how the error changes with respect to
所以表示错误相对于每个权重如何变化的梯度都一样
each weight are also all the same and can't tell us anything.
不能向我们提供任何有效信息
We have a really hard time finding out which weights should be updated and by how much.
我们很难判断哪些权重应该更新 更新多少
Something similar happens if the weights are all initialized as ones.
有时候权重全初始化为 1 时也会出现类似情况
When the weights are all ones,
当权重全为 1 时
then again you're going to have your input pixel values
输入像素值需要
multiplied by one and summed in a hidden node.
在隐藏节点中乘以 1 并求和
Again, the hidden layer calculations are going to be the
当输入在 MLP 层级中向前移动时
same as inputs moved forward through the MLP layers.
隐藏层的计算结果也一样
When we try to identify sources of error, we can't really.
这就导致我们无法确定错误来源
So, after two epics,
因此在两轮训练后
I'm also recording the validation accuracy of these two models.
我也开始记录这两个模型的验证准确率
We can see about 9.7 and 10.2
对于全初始化为 0 和全为 1 的模型
accuracy for the all zeros and all ones initialization models.
分别约为 9.7% 和 10.2%
That means that these networks are getting in like one 1 out of 10 classes correct.
表明这些网络在 10 个类别中大概有 1 个分类正确
For a 10 class problem,
对于像 Fashion-MNIST 这样仅有 10  个识别类别的任务
as our fashion M-ness task is,
这种验证准确率
that's the equivalent of guessing one class randomly out of 10.
相当于随机地从 10 个类别中猜测出一个
So, this is really bad.
效果简直太差了
In fact, the zeros model is not even randomly guessing.
实际上 全为 0 的模型甚至不是随机猜测
It's just guessing that same class over and over again.
只是不断猜测相同的类别
I should note that initializing with all ones seems particularly bad,
要提一下 全初始化为 1 的效果尤其差
and this is because ones are really too high of a starting value,
这是因为 1 是很高的起点值
so the backpropagation algorithm has
反向传播算法
an especially hard time bringing those values
很难将这些值变小
down and getting to the minimum of the loss.
并达到损失的最低值
So, these constant weights are basically just performing really poorly,
因此这些常量权重效果很差
but it's still helpful to see this behavior through a critical lens.
但是依然有助于我们了解这种行为
Again, because our weights are all the same,
因为权重都一样
that means the activations of all our units in the hidden layers are also all the same.
因此隐藏层中所有单元的激活函数也一样
So, the backprop algorithm struggles to minimize the loss.
反向传播算法很难降低损失值
Using constant initial weights essentially sets up
使用常量初始权重本质上会使反向传播失败
backpropagation to fail because it's not designed to deal with consistency.
因为反向传播本身就不能处理一致性情况
Backprop is designed to look at how different weight values affect the training loss.
它是为了查看不同的权重值对训练损失有何影响
So, how might we change our initial weighting scheme so that we set up
那么该如何更改初始权重策略
the backpropagation algorithm to succeed and
使反向传播算法能成功
better differentiate between the effect of different weights?
并更好地区分不同权重的影响？
I want you to think about this question,
请思考这个问题
and then we'll talk about a few more effective and common initialization schemes.
接下来我们将讨论其他几个有效的常见初始化策略